# 哈喽大家好
Hello guys
# 因为快过年了嘛
It's gonna be Chinese New Year soon
# 现在我买了点这个对联
Now I've bought some red paper for writing "Dui Lian" (spring couplet: decoration that expresses hopeful thoughts for the new year )
# 让我老爸自己写 写来贴一下
My father will write on it, and we put it up on the doorway
# 因为自己新房子修起来不想到外面买所以就自己写
Because this is our new house, we decided not to buy "Dui Lian" from vendors. Instead, we will write them ourselves
# 买了一些来练就当练练手法
We've got a bit more paper for practicing
# 你写嘛
Go on, you write it
# 第一句叫什么
What's the first line?
# 万紫千红
Innumerable colourful flowers...
# 啊
Huh?
# 万紫千红
"Wan Zi Qian Hong" (lit. Innumerable flowers of red and purple)
# 春色满园
"Chun Se Man Yuan" (lit. The garden is full of spring landscape)
# 咋子感觉有点逛（光滑）呢
Why does it seem a bit glossy?
# 哎呀不得行
Aiya, it's not working
# 这个纸有点逛
The paper is too glossy
# 好了现在我们重新调了墨水
It's fine now. We use a different mixture of ink
# 重新来
Let's start again
# 这下子你要写慢点
This time you may need to slow down your writing a little
# 快了可能不得行
It won't do if you write it too fast
# 哦 要得蘸哈（墨水）
Ohhh, it works! Dip your brush in
# 可以
Not bad!
# 这个字是啥子字啊
What does this character read?
# 万字啥
It's "Wan" (lit. ten thousand)
# 我还认不到
I cannot tell
# 慢慢拉这个笔
Pull the stroke slowly
# 不要拉（写）快了 好又蘸墨水
Don't be too hasty...Ok dip the brush in
# 慢慢拉（写）
Take it easy
# 噢 它是每个圈圈里写一个字
Oh, it's like...each circle for one character
# 哦 它是固定的
Oh, the position is fixed
# 慢慢来
Take it easy
# 我忍不住要笑
I can't help laughing
# 这咋子不对头哦
It seems not right
# 这才几个字哦
How many characters are there?
# 万紫千红哦
"Wan Zi Qian Hong"
# 万 紫 千 红 春
"Wan", "Zi", "Qian", "Hong", "Chun"
# 满
"Man"
# 玉吗
Is it "Yu"?
# 你是记性不好来写什么字都搞忘记了
Your memory is so bad that you even forget what character to write
# 慢点
Take your time
# 不是墨供应不上
The ink isn't fast enough
# 慢慢写
Take it easy
# 可能是笔尖尖上墨不够
Probably the tip of brush is lacking ink
# 还有写重了也有可能
You might have pressed the brush too hard
# 嗯 还可以
Hmm, not bad
# 看一下
Let's have a look
# 要流哦（墨水）
Watch out! (The ink) is dripping!
# 等它 晒一会儿多
Wait a moment. Let it dry up
# 放地上晒一会儿
Place it on the ground and let it dry up
# 我一看到这个我就想起
At the sight of this I immediately thought of
# 天下武功 唯快不破
"Tian Xia Wu Gong, Wei Kuai Bu Po" (lit. Speed is the only key to crack Kung Fu)
# 你给老子（这里还有一点对话没有字幕，也听不出来在说啥）
You... # 中文字幕不完整，那我们也就这样吧
# 好
Cool
# 好 这个字是啥子啊
What is this character?
# 哪个字哦
Which one?
# 这一幅叫啥子安
What does this scroll read?
# 五讲四美展新艳
"Wu Jiang Zi Mei Zhan Xin Yan" (lit. Cultivated in good manners, displaying a new prospect)
# 叫啥子安 五长啥子安
What is that?
# 五讲 四美展新艳
5 stresses (decorum, manners, hygiene, discipline, morals), 4 beauties (mind, language, behavior, environment)
# 后面这个明显要比刚刚要好一点
This latter scroll looks apparently better than the first one
# 可能是很久没写有点紧张
Probably I'm a bit nervous. It's been quite a while since last time I wrote a pair of "Dui Lian"
# 好 现在我们开始写横批
Okay, now we're gonna write "Heng Pi" (lit. the horizonal banner)
# 恭贺新禧
"Gong He Xin Xi" (lit. Happy New Year)
# 张灯结彩迎新春
"Zhang Deng Jie Cai Ying Xin Chun" (lit. Embracing the new spring with lanterns and colourful decoration)
# 好 那下一句呢
Good. What's the next line then?
# 来嘛 四伯爷放在这边
This way, uncle put it here
# 好 这个横批也写好了
Okay, now our "Heng Pi" is finished
# 翻过来看
Turn it around and see
# 这里没写到
It's missing a stroke here
# 来看一下
Have a look
# 喜字没写好
The "Xi" character is not right
# 喜迎新春
"Xi Ying Xin Chun" (Another expression for "Happy New Year")
# 新年 真的这个新年快到了
New Year, truly, this new year is coming
# 现在等一下干了之后把它贴上去
Wait a moment. When the writing is dried, I'll put up "Dui Lian"
# 贴上去就可以了
And it's all done
# 因为这是第一次在新房过年嘛
Because this is the first Chinese New Year we spend in the new house
# 对联就自己写
We write our own "Dui Lian"
# 就等它干
Waiting until it dries up
# 不慌 还要重新来(写)
No worries, I will write again
# 没写好
It's not perfect
# 我老爸对自己要求有一点高
My father is a bit strict with himself
# 他要再写一遍
He's gonna write it once again
# 笔尖有点发叉
The bristles are somewhat split
# 笔没得好好得
Not a good brush?
# 嗯 好又写了一个
Um, good. Another one is done
# 喜迎新春
"Xi Ying Xin Chun" (Another expression for "Happy New Year")
# 满不满意这次
Are you satisfied this time?
# 不满意啊
No?
# 我觉得还可以啊你咋子对自己不满意啊
Why? I think it looks nice
# 四伯爷是不是
Aren't they, uncle?
# 四伯爷你看斗满不满意
Have a look, uncle. How do you feel about it?
# 可以噶
It's fine
# 马马虎虎
Not bad
# 我害怕冒火我还是写一个
Let me still try to write one
# 你写来试一下嘛
Have a try!
# 我照着写嘛
I need to copy these
# 算了等会儿别人要笑
Forget about it. People would laugh at me
# 我的书本来就读得不多
I haven't read much books
# 你让我拿这个炒勺炒菜可以
You can ask me to take up this stir-fry spoon and cook
# 你让我拿毛笔写字的话
If you ask me to pick up brush and do calligraphy
# 可能真的有点差强人意
It wouldn't turn out well
# 高
"Gao" (lit. skillful)
# 厨
"Chu" (lit. chef)
# 高厨
"Gao Chu"
# 来 你们看一下这个上联
Come here and have a look at this first line
# 高厨巧做三鲜美
"Gao Chu Qiao Zuo San Xian Mei" (lit. Skillful chef turns three delicacies into tasty dishes)
# 这个是厨师家里面必备的一张
This is a classic line for chefs
# 好 下联第一个字也是厨
Okay, the first character of the second line is also "Chu"
# 好 下联也写好了
Good. The second scroll is finished
# 看一下
Take a look
# 厨内精心调五味
"Chu Nei Jing Xin Tiao Wu Wei" (lit. Handling five flavours with skills and care)
"Chu Nei Jing Xin Tiao Wu Wei"
# 这几个字充分说明这个是贴在厨房门口
These lines make it evident that they are to be posted on the kitchen doorway
# 好 让它干一会儿
Okay, let it dry up
# 还是要那个自己磨的墨
We should use the ink made by ourselves
# 色味俱佳
"Se Wei Ju Jia" (lit. excellent in both color and flavour)
# 差不多了噶
It's almost done
# 等它干了我们拿来粘
Let's put it up after it's dried
# 还可以
It's not bad
# 至少我写不到这么好
At least I cannot write as good
# 等会儿拿什么来粘呢 四伯爷
Uncle, what are we gonna use to stick the scrolls on the wall
# 拿点饭来粘撒
Just take some rice
# 剩饭啊
Leftover?
# 是啊 没得胶水得
Yeah, we ain't got no glue here
# 放在上面按啊
So I should press the rice onto the scroll
# 要贴在中间哦
Put it right in the middle!
# 得不得行
Are you alright
# 应该没得好大的问题得
Shouldn't be a big problem
# 用拳头敲嘛
Use your fist to press it
# 高一点点嘛
Move it a little higher
# 这里嘛
Here?
# 哦噢 对对对
Oh right
# 好 贴了哦
Good. So be it
# 反正要对称那个门框
It needs to align with the door frame
# 基本上对称了的
It's basically matched
# 跟那边也要平起
It should form a symmetry with the other side
# 在门上你写不写几个字嘛
Do you wanna write a few characters on the door?
# 还是一个门框上写一个福字嘛
One "Fu" character for each door? ("Fu": fortune, blessing, happiness)
# 好 火炮拿来放起过年了
Good. Take up your firecrackers and prepare for New Year celebration!
喜迎新春
"Xi Ying Xin Chun" ("Happy New Year")
# 万紫千红春满园
"Wan Zi Qian Hong Chun Man Yuan" ("Thousands of red and purple flowers filling the garden with spring landscape")
# 五讲四美展新艳
"Wu Jiang Zi Mei Zhan Xin Yan" ("Cultivated in good manners, displaying a new prospect")
# 这样贴起是要好看点安
It looks much better with "Dui Lian"
# 好 我们的对联就差不多就写完了
Okay. Our "Dui Lian" is almost finished
# 还有几天就过年了
Chinese New Year is coming in a few days
# 在这里就提前祝大家新春快乐啦
Here in advance, we wish you a happy new year
# 本期视频就到这里
This is all for today's video
# 拜拜
Bye Bye!